# **Anthony Marshall**





# **Personal Details**

Address : Howick, Auckland 2014 Date of Birth : 17 December 1981

Nationality : New Zealand Current Age : 35

Email Address : anthonymarshall@gmail.com Phone : 027 658 4855

LinkedIn Profile: linkedin.com/in/anthonymarshallnz

Portfolio Site : anthonymarshall.io

# **About Me**

I'm a software developer who has recently settled back in Auckland, New Zealand, after having spent the last 5 years living in London, UK. I have 14 years commercial experience building many successful web and desktop based applications for a wide variety of companies and industries.

In 2003 I graduated from Auckland University of Technology with a bachelor's degree in Applied Science.

My key technical experiences revolve around (but not limited to) both back and front end web development using the Microsoft stack of technologies. i.e C#, Asp.net, Sql Server, Html, CSS, JS (Angular)

# **Education**

2000 – 2003 : <u>Auckland University of Technology</u>

**Bachelor of Applied Science Majoring in Computer Science** 

# **Software Technology Experience**

	Years Experience								
Technology	< 1	1	2	3	4	5	6+		
C# .Net							•		
ASP.Net MVC / Web Forms									
WPF .Net									
SQL Server									

	1	1		1		 1
SQL DTS, SSIS, SSRS						
Crystal Reports					•	
Web frontend (HTML\CSS\JS\SASS\Angular)						•
React JS						
PHP						
MySQL						
Oracle 9i and 10g			•			
GIT			•			
Linux Administration						
Team City (Continuous Integration)						
Team Foundation Server (TFS)					•	
Development Team Management				•		
Technical Lead						

#### Other Skills

- Exceptional verbal and written communication skills.
- Excellent time management skills and practices.
- Extensive client liaison and user training experience.
- Ability to quickly learn and adapt new development technologies.
- Extensive experience managing and mentoring developers.
- Experience writing client facing technical documentation.
- Ability and experience in successfully architecting simple technical solutions for complex problems.

# **Work Experience**

# BBD Perfect Storm London (<u>bbdperfectstorm.com</u>) (formerly Suburb Design London <u>wearesuburb.com</u>)

September 2012 - December 2016

Technical Director / Senior Developer (permanent role)

I undertook a dual role of Technical Director and Senior Developer at Suburb. My time was spent approximately 50/50 between these two roles.

Key responsibilities were to help develop both front and back end software systems, manage the software development team (5 devs), define product development processes, drive R & D ventures, technical contact for liaising with clients and give direction on IT related strategies, planning and resources.

Some key clients that I have worked with in this role are Investec, BP, Cadburys, Samsung, Converse, Japanese Tobacco International, De Beers and Kinder.

# Candi London (candi.co.uk)

June 2012 - August 2012

Freelance Senior .Net Developer (short-term contract)

London based digital agency. My role here was to help build new modules for the Morrison supermart website <a href="https://www.morrisons.co.uk">www.morrisons.co.uk</a>

#### **Suburb Design London (<u>wearesuburb.com</u>)**

January 2012 - June 2012

Freelance Senior .Net Developer (short-term contract)

Suburb are a digital agency based in London who specialise in interactive art direction and design, website design and development, and social media app development.

I am currently working here as a contract developer and have been involved in a number of projects coding (front and back-end) highly interactive, advertising campaign based websites and Facebook applications.

The fast paced nature of projects and tight deadlines in digital agencies such as Suburb allowed me to demonstrate that I was capable of producing quality code in a timely fashion to meet project demands.

Such sites I have worked on in this role are:

- <u>www.cadburydairymilk.co.uk</u> Cadbury's UK Joyville website
- <u>www.bigsocietycapital.com</u> Big Society Capital website launched by former UK PM David Cameron to support government big society funding.

# AIMIA (<u>aimia.com</u>) (formerly Carlson Marketing Ltd)

June 2007 – October 2011

#### Senior Analyst Programmer

AIMIA (formerly Carlson Marketing Ltd) is a world leading provider of customer and business loyalty programmes for many high profile multi-national companies, such as Vodafone, Westpac Bank and Pfizer. In this role I was part of a team who have successfully developed a number of high-traffic, 100,000+ user, web based systems.

Also in this role, I was fortunate enough to have taken part in a 3 month secondment to work at the Carlson Marketing Ltd head office in Minnesota, US. The experience I gained from this has proved to be extremely valuable, as it gave me great exposure to working on IT projects on a global scale and helped validate my development skills and knowledge in an environment outside of New Zealand

Such systems that I have worked on include:

- <u>www.hotpoints.co.nz</u> Westpac bank's customer loyalty points redemption site
- <u>www.truerewards.co.nz</u> ASB bank's customer loyalty points redemption site
- <u>www.int-agent.com</u> Avis Budget Group's multi-lingual rental car reservation system for the Latin America market.

Key technologies used in this position: ASP.Net, C#.Net, VB.Net, Visual Studio, SQL Server 2000, 2005 and 2008, SQL DTS and SSIS

#### Key Responsibilities:

- Application development of high traffic, front-end and back-end transactional systems
- Application user interface design
- Database design and development

- B2B EDI design, development and implementation
- Technical documentation
- Implementation of multi-lingual systems
- Training and support for junior developers
- Liaising with external clients and in-house account managers
- Sourcing best-fit technologies to support product development
- Migration of legacy systems into modern development platforms (e.g Fox Pro -> .Net)

# Kinetiq Ltd (www.kinetiq.com)

January 2005 - June 2007

# **Analyst Programmer**

Kinetiq Ltd is an industry-leading provider of web and desktop based data management solutions for the international energy market. In this role I was the technical lead in a large project building a web based process management solution. I also help manage and develop a number of our other major software products.

Key technologies used in this position: ASP.Net, C#.Net, VB.Net, Visual Studio 2003 and 2005, SQL Server 2000 and 2005 and Oracle 10g

#### Key Responsibilities:

- Application development of front-end and back-end transactional systems
- Application user interface design
- Database design and development
- Training and support for junior developers
- Liaising with external clients and in-house account managers
- Sourcing best-fit technologies to support product development
- Training end-users

#### **Edis International Ltd**

May 2004 - December 2004

# Software Developer

In this position I was hired as a software developer to work on developing B2B EDI message translation applications that work closely with various ERP systems. Messaging standards that I have become familiar with in this role were XML, ANSI x12 and EDIFACT. I was also responsible for other tasks within the organisation such as the development of EdisInternational.com website and software product testing.

Key technologies used in this position: VB6, VB.Net, ASP, Pervasive and SQL Server.

#### Key Responsibilities:

- Application development of front-end and back-end transactional systems
- Application user interface design
- Database design and development
- Training and support for junior developers
- Training end-users
- Migration of legacy systems into modern development platforms (e.g VB6 -> .Net)

# **Blueday Ltd**

May 2003 - May 2004

# Software Developer

This was my first full-time position as an IT professional. I specialised in web and software development for small to medium sized businesses. This role involved a number of responsibilities relating to the development of successful IT solutions.

Key technologies used in this position: ASP, ASP.net and SQL Server.

#### Key Responsibilities:

- Application development of front-end and back-end transactional systems
- Application user interface design
- Database design and development
- Liaising with external clients

# **Online Talent Agency**

August 2002 - July 2003

# Student software developer

In the final year research and development project for my degree, I was involved the development of a web-based system, which enabled my client (Background Talent. Talent agency that specialises in managing extras, actors and production crews for TV and Film) to perform key business processes through a highly functional web application. This system has proved to be highly successful in providing significant growth in business for my client. Software products developed in this project is still being used today.

Key technologies used in this position: PHP, MySQL and Apache.

#### References

# Paul Kelly (Head of Interactive Design - Suburb / BBD Perfect Storm London)

Email: paul.kelly@wearesuburb.com

Phone: +44 20 7234 0637

# Nigel Manson (Senior Developer - Suburb / BBD Perfect Storm London)

Email: nigel.manson@wearesuburb.com

Phone: +44 20 7234 0637

# Danny Daley (Head of Digital - Suburb / BBD Perfect Storm London)

Email: danny@wearesuburb.com

Phone: +44 20 7234 0637

# Ivan Sentch (IT Manager - Aimia New Zealand)

Email: ivan.sentch@aimia.co.nz

Phone: +64 21 2538880